Lionel Robin

Senior Full-stack | Blockchain Engineer

- 🔀 lionel.robin528@gmail.com 💡 Eichenzell, HE, Germany 🔭 lionel528.netlify.app
- in linkedin.com/in/lionelrobin528 💆 @lionelrobin528 😯 github.com/icedev528

OVERVIEW

Lionel is a senior full-stack | blockchain developer with a broad and versatile coding skill set.

He loves to write code in a high-paced and challenging environment with an emphasis on using best practices to develop high-quality software that meets project requirements, budget, and schedule.

He has worked with tech companies for over 6 years, helping to build technology-based businesses from the ground up.

His strong theoretical and practical background in IT, business consulting, and project management makes him extremely capable of projects of any size.

As a full-stack developer, He has been collaborating with a variety of companies including small startups and big communities, which has made him intimately familiar with all the stages of the web lifecycle from the initial architecture to final deployment.

He enjoys learning new technologies and sharing findings with his colleagues.

Lionel is the go-to guy for any of your development needs.

He worked in software engineering for his entire 6-year career, and his commitment to critical thinking and attention to detail has gotten him to where he is today: A senior software engineer for First.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cosmic Universe | EvoVerses | Kortstrid

05/2022 - 06/2023 | US

Senior Front-end | Blockchain Engineer

Cosmic Universe, EvoVerses, Kortstrid are partners leading the blockchain industry especially metaverse and game.

Cosmic Universe is a fantasy blockchain metaverse world-builder and MMORPG with tradable NFTs on the Avalanche blockchain. It is an immersive fantasy metaverse adventure MMORPG where players explore realms, gather, harvest, mine, develop increasingly-advanced plots and settlements, trade, level up for magical powers and in-game rewards, and engage in PVP competitions and events.

EvoVerses aims to forge the perfect fusion between DeFi and GameFi. To achieve this, our team is working in Unreal Engine 5 to create a game that mixes beautiful and realistic graphics with fun animated cartoons. The game revolves around mystical and fabulous creatures named Evos. In addition, our project will also include a set of decentralized finance tools and services.

Kortstrid is an innovative trading card game (TCG) that brings together the excitement of strategic card gameplay with the powerful benefits of decentralized technology. In Kortstrid, players collect, trade, and battle with unique digital cards and assets, able to be represented by a digitally stored asset solely owned by the player who owns the account. The game incorporates a rich, immersive storyline, diverse card types, and engaging gameplay mechanics, providing a captivating experience for both casual and dedicated players.

- Developed the NFT marketplace for Cosmic Universe game wizards, elves, and other fantasy characters, items, and cards on Avalanche and Harmony network.
- Built the website using modern JavaScript framework React and implemented original features such as server side rendering, static rendering by Next.js.
- Made pixel-perfect and mobile-friendly responsive website using Material UI and Tailwind CSS, styled components.
- Optimized the website performance and web3 calls, and API endpoints using React Hook.
- Handled the heavy development of embedded JavaScript widgets on third-party publisher sites.
- Worked with nested iframes, asynchronous loading of NFT data, and size/scaling issues for mobile, and error-handling.
- Created robust marketplace that reliably loaded, retired, and gracefully handled in multiple browsers and platforms.
- Version controlled by Git and deployed through Google Cloud Platform.

Products:

Technologies:

React.js, Redux, Next.js, JavaScript / TypeScript, Material UI, Styled components, Tailwind CSS, NFT Marketplace, Avalanche / Harmony, GitHub, Figma, Google Cloud Platform

CropperFinance

09/2021 – 12/2022 | France

Lead Front-end | Blockchain Engineer

Decentralized Ecosystem that Empowers Projects & Maximizes Yield to move Defi forward on Solana. Swap, Yield Farming, Staking, IDO Launchpad & more.

- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility. Developed standard and ad hoc report in graph format as required.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Integrated functionalities with the Blockchain network including a wallet and Solana programs.

Products:

https://cropper.finance

https://meeiro.xyz ☑

Technologies:

Vue.js, Nuxt.js, JavaScript / TypeScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Ant D, Solana, Web3.js, Figma, GitHub

Shmacked 🛮

03/2020 - 09/2021 | US

Senior Full-stack Engineer

Shmacked offers unmatched convenience by delivering everything from snacks, drinks, nicotine, and alcohol in less than 15 minutes.

- Improved functionalities and pipeline integration by designing and implementing cross-platform frameworks.
- Contributed to an ~18% rise in subscribers MoM for 6 months by enhancing the user's experience on all supported client platforms.
- Ensured tight cooperation with other engineers, designers, and artists through active listening, frequent communication, and leadership skills.
- Fixed bugs and problems across the entire codebase efficiently and promptly.

Products:

https://shmacked.com 🗷

Technologies:

React.js, JavaScript / TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, GitHub, Netlify, Google Cloud Platform, Figma

Janus Network | Smaugs

04/2020 – 12/2022 | Germany

Senior Front-end | Web3 Engineer

Smaugs Marketplace is a complete custom DeFi, governance, and NFT ecosystem + marketplace.

Janus Network is a private blockchain for gaming and defi applications that leverages Avalanche Network's existing infrastructure and security.

- Developed the NFT marketplace for Smaugs NFTs and Janus Network.
- Optimized the website performance and web3 calls, API endpoints using React Hook.
- Built the responsive and user friendly website using React.js.
- Implemented the static rendering and server side rendering from Next.js.
- Worked with blockchain concepts and products such as DeFi and DEX.

Products:

https://janusnetwork.io

Technologies:

React.js, Next.js, JavaScript / TypeScript, Web3.js, Ether.js, DeFi, NFT Marketplace.

Senior Full-stack Engineer

Since 2014 Creativ-cult has been on the market with fresh, creative, and innovative ideas to inspire our customers with our graphic design. We also like to go unconventional ways to find the best solutions for our projects. We are not normal and conventional - we think differently and are a little bit crazy - just CULT.

- Led a cross-functional team of 10 to develop software solutions for clients.
- Communicate with clients to determine technical requirements and develop plans within an Agile environment to provide solutions on time and within budget.
- Utilize extensive knowledge of user testing to ensure high-quality, functional software solutions are delivered to clients.

Products:

https://creativ-cult.de

https://lunch4you.de 🛮

https://pizzadays.de 🖪

https://mr-lunch.de 🗹

https://sevendays.de 🛮

https://das5element.de 🗷

Technologies:

PHP, Laravel, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Adobe Photoshop, Bitbucket, AWS

Trackd Music 🗆

11/2016 - 01/2017 | United Kingdom

Junior Front-end Engineer

Trackd[®] is the Award-Winning Social Music App uniting both Music Artists and music lovers.

- Liaised with clients to gain a thorough understanding of their needs and goals and generated effective software solutions to their problems
- Assisted with writing Vue and TypeScript code for applications and software testing
- Provided ongoing technical support and troubleshooting services, making system improvements when necessary

Products:

https://trackdmusic.com

Technologies:

Vue.js, JavaScript / TypeScript, Vuetify, Firebase, Node.js, Figma, GitHub



Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, ECMAScript (ES5, ES6), PHP, Python, Ruby, C/C++, C#, Java

Backend Frameworks

Node.js / Express, Laravel, Symfony, Codelgniter, Django, Flask, FastAPI, Ruby on Rails

Testing Frameworks

Jest, Mocha, Cypress

Platforms

Docker, AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase

API Development

RESTful APIs, GraphQL, Postman

Additional Libraries

D3.js, Chart.js, Mapbox,js, Leaflet.js, Swiper.js

EDUCATION

Nanyang Technological University

Bachelor's Degree of Computer Science

2013 - 2016 | Singapore

Frontend Frameworks

Angular, React.js / Redux, Next.js, Gatsby, Vue.js / Vuex, Nuxt.js, Quasar, jQuery

UI Component Libraries

Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, SASS, LESS, Material UI, Ant D, Chakra UI, Vuetify, React Bootstrap, Bootstrap Vue

Storage

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Redis

Version Control

Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, GitLab

Blockchain

Web3.js, Ether.js, Solidity, Rust, Hardhat, Truffle, Remix, NFT, DEFI, DEX, Ethereum, Solana, Boba Network

LANGUAGES

English

Chinese





INTERESTS

Learning Programming

I enjoys learning new programming languages and taking on challenges through online platforms such as HackerRank and Turing.

As a professional, I continuously learning in the ever-evolving field of programming.

I actively explore new technologies, frameworks, and libraries to expand my skill set and stay up-to-date with the latest industry trends.

Sports

As a passionate fan of FIFA and NBA, I eagerly engage in friendly matches and games with my friends, further fueling my love for these sports.

By incorporating my passion for FIFA and NBA into my personal life, I have cultivated a strong sense of sportsmanship, healthy competition, and the drive to constantly improve myself.